

Software Developer.

CONTACT INFO

maxwittek+resume@gmail.com Brooklyn, NY

ONLINE

github.com/wittekm LinkedIn @wwiimmaaxx

SKILLS

As this list grows, it's easiest to say that I pick up new technologies and practices pretty easily.

Rust Python Typescript w/ React

Relational DBs Graph DBs Time series DBs

(out of practice:)
Golang
Java
C++14
Ruby w/ Rails

Profile

Full-stack software engineer with 10+ years experience in building distributed services, native libraries, and frontend experiences. I'm happiest when improving a well-tested, statically typed codebase, at an exciting and ethical company (an immediate 'no thank you' to adtech or investment firms - sorry!).

Experience

Datadog (2022+)

Senior Software Engineer

Working on the Cloud Security Posture Management product.

Grapl Security (2020-2022)

Founding Software Engineer

Startup in the cybersecurity space, creating a next-generation SIEM modeling risk interactions in a graph database. (Team hired by Datadog!)

Oropbox (2015-2020)

Software Engineer 2 & 3

<u>Tech lead</u> on our Slack integration, Gmail addon and Azure Active Directory integration. Primarily owned task management and architecture for these projects, but I still code ~50% of my time. Frequently worked with external business partners/engineers at Slack, Microsoft and Google.

Engineer on Dropbox's open-source client-side metrics and aggregation solution, working with TSDBs, Kafka, etc.

Developer responsible for worldwide payments processing, product catalog, ETLs, revenue reporting, and compliance.

a Amazon.com (2012-2015)

Software Development Engineer I & II

Worked on portions of the Kindle cross-platform layout & rendering engine in C++03.

Tech: worked with Boost libraries, OpenGL ES, Android NDK and Cocoa.

Member of the Kindle Content Inspection & Automation team, developing technology to ensure that only quality books are made available on the Kindle Store, and that publishers have the rights to the content.

Internships

Amazon.com (2011), Crestron Electronics (2009), BlackRock Solutions (2008)

Education

University of Michigan (2008-2012)

Bachelors of Science in Engineering, Computer Science

Relevant classes included UI Development, Intro to Artificial Intelligence, Advanced Programming and Design Patterns, Operating Systems, Computer Organization/Architecture, Data Structures & Algorithms, Natural Language Processing.